Captioning Provided By:
MTV Networks
字幕提供者：
MTV网络
Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Price check on industrial size
econo-pack of raw fiber.
工业规模价格检查
原纤维经济包装。
It goes in like steel wool
它像钢丝绒一样插入
but comes out like
an angel from heaven.
但结果就像
来自天堂的天使。
Please, tell me more.
请告诉我更多。
Ooh, well,
this one time...
哦，好吧，
这一次...
Not really.
并不真地。
I didn't think so.
我不这么认为。
Oh, wait, I almost
forgot me coupons.
哦，等等，我几乎
忘记给我优惠券了。
There's a couple double
ones in there, too.
有一对双人的
那里也有。
Sir, these expired
over 30 years ago.
先生，这些已经过期了
30多年前。
What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
It means they're not good.
这说明他们不好。
Sir, I'll just throw
those away for you.
先生，我就扔
那些为你而远去的人。
No, wait, I'll take 'em.
不，等等，我会接受他们。
OK, sir, your change today
好的，先生，您今天换了
is going to be exactly 10 cents.
正好是 10 美分。
Come to papa,
come to papa.
来到爸爸身边，
来找爸爸吧。
Hooray!
万岁！
Two Nickels.
两枚镍币。
Hey, that's SpongeBob out there.
嘿，那是海绵宝宝。
What in blue blazes
is that boy up to?
蓝色火焰里有什么
那个男孩在做什么？
Well, I'll be
a geriatric jellyfish.
嗯，我会的
一种老年水母。
SpongeBob found a penny.
海绵宝宝找到了一分钱。
A bright, shiny penny
just sitting there
一枚明亮闪亮的便士
就坐在那里
and he picked it right up.
他马上把它捡了起来。
I can remember
the whole thing
我记得
整个事情
as if it had just
happened a moment ago.
就好像它刚刚
发生在刚才。
Sir,  sir?
先生，先生？
Sir?
先生？
You're holding
up the line.
你拿着
上线。
Oh, I am?
哦，我是？
Next, please.
接下来请。
Interesting how things
work out that way.
有趣的是事情如何
就这样锻炼吧。
Some folks just walk along
and stumble over free money
有些人只是走着走着
并偶然发现了免费的钱
while others...
Others, they work.
而其他人...
其他人，他们工作。
Hey, Mommy, look
at that weird guy
嘿，妈妈，你看
在那个奇怪的家伙
in the car over there.
在那边的车里。
Billy, mommy's watching
the road right now.
比利，妈妈在看着
现在的路。
I mean, why couldn't  I  have
just walked along and found it?
我的意思是，为什么我不能
刚刚走过去就发现了？
I have legs too, you know.
我也有腿，你知道的。
: Ooh.
：哦。
How 'bout a little music?
来点音乐怎么样？
: Oh, wha!
：哦，哇！
OK, OK, get a grip, Krabs.
好吧，好吧，抓紧，蟹蟹。
Just concentrate on driving.
专心驾驶即可。
Ah!
啊!
OK.
好的。
Getting all worked up
over one little coin.
全力以赴
超过一枚小硬币。
Ah, must just be the full moon.
啊，一定是满月吧。
Wait a second.
等一下。
I gotta
我必须
have that
有那个
penny!
一分钱！
Good morning, SpongeBob.
早上好，海绵宝宝。
Good morning, Mr. Krabs.
早上好，蟹老板。
Find anything
special, lately?
找到任何东西
最近，特别吗？
Yeah-yes.
是的，是的。
Really?
真的吗？
And you want to share it
并且你想分享它
with your old Uncle Krabs,
don't you, boy?
和你的老螃蟹叔叔，
你不是吗，孩子？
Of course.
当然。
Great.
伟大的。
Well, share it with me.
嗯，和我分享一下吧。
I already am sharing
it with you, Mr. Krabs.
我已经在分享了
蟹老板，和你一起吧。
What?
什么？
The thing I found
我发现的东西
was a bright, shiny
是明亮的、有光泽的
new day!
新的一天！
Well, I'll be in the
kitchen if you need me.
嗯，我会在
厨房，如果你需要我的话。
SpongeBob:
Morning, Squidward.
海绵宝宝：
早上好，章鱼哥。
Don't talk to me.
别跟我说话。
Mr. Krabs seems to be
in a good mood today.
蟹老板先生好像是
今天心情很好。
That counts as talking.
这才算说话。
Whoa, hello again,
Mr. Krabs.
哇，又好，
蟹老板。
Hello, SpongeBob.
你好，海绵宝宝。
What can I do you for?
我能为你做什么？
Can I borrow
a penny?
我可以借吗
一分钱？
Sure.
当然。
Hm, sorry.
嗯，抱歉。
All out of pennies right now.
现在已经没钱了。
But did you check
all your pockets?
但你检查过吗
你的口袋里都有吗？
Well, I thought I did.
嗯，我想我做到了。
Front pockets?
前袋？
Hm, no.
嗯，不。
Um-um.
嗯嗯。
Nada.
没什么。
Shoe pockets.
鞋袋。
Oh, Mr. Krabs, that
is just ridiculous.
哦，蟹老板，那个
太荒谬了。
It is?
这是？
Oh, I do have
a tie pocket, though.
哦，我有
不过，还有一个领带口袋。
No, not in there, either.
不，也不在那里。
Hey, maybe it fell
in your sock.
嘿嘿，可能是掉下来了
在你的袜子里。
Well, I...
嗯，我...
:
It's just gotta
：
只是必须
be in there somewhere
在那里某处
to get, to get that...
得到，得到那个…
Uh...
呃...
It's my brain.
这是我的大脑。
Hey, where's it going?
嘿，它要去哪儿？
SpongeBob: Oh, there.
海绵宝宝：哦，在那里。
SpongeBob: Look there,
look that way... There.
海绵宝宝：看那儿，
朝那个方向看……那里。
Both: I got it.
两人：我明白了。
SpongeBob: I got it,
I got it, I got it.
海绵宝宝：我明白了
我明白了，我明白了。
Aha.
啊哈。
Ugh.
啊。
SpongeBob: Not so fast,
little guy.
海绵宝宝：没那么快，
小家伙。
:
There you go...
：
就这样吧...
...look, huh?
……你看，嗯？
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道。
Uh...
呃...
Didn't you know
I was a brain whisperer?
你不知道吗
我是个脑语者？
So, uh,
no penny, huh?
所以，呃，
没有一分钱吧？
Darn.
该死。
Squidward, these deafening
construction sounds
章鱼哥，这些震耳欲聋的
施工声音
are preventing me from working.
妨碍我工作。
Me too.
我也是。
You think we should walk
out back to investigate?
你认为我们应该步行
回去调查？
Never.
绝不。
SpongeBob: The sounds were
coming from back here.
海绵宝宝：声音是
从这里回来。
What the!
什么啊！
Careful with
those marquee letters.
小心
那些字幕字母。
Hey, Mr. Krabs, you made
your own movie theater.
嘿，蟹老板，你做了
你自己的电影院。
Yes, I did.
是的，我做到了。
And you're just in time
for the grand opening.
而你来得正是时候
为盛大开幕。
Step right up, folks.
站起来，伙计们。
And witness a spellbinding tale
chockful of adventure.
见证一个引人入胜的故事
充满冒险。
And action...
还有行动...
And thrills.
和刺激。
You know, I'm not
really hungry.
你知道，我不是
真的很饿。
Yeah, let's go see what this
fat guy is yelling about.
是啊，我们去看看这是什么
胖子正在大喊大叫。
Witness the
terrifying challenges
见证
可怕的挑战
overcome by, by...
克服, 被...
By who?
由谁来？
By, uh...
靠，呃...
By a plucky
young sponge.
由一个勇敢的
年轻的海绵。
Just like me.
就像我一样。
That's right.
这是正确的。
And the best part Is
最好的部分是
admission is only
one penny.
入场仅
一分钱。
Does a movie
like that even exist?
拍电影吗
这样的事还存在吗？
Yeah, does it?
是啊，是吗？
Um... Well, actually, I was
gonna show you this flip book.
嗯...好吧，实际上，我是
给你看这本翻书。
A flip book.
一本翻书。
Yeah, I don't even
know what that  is!
是的，我什至不
知道那是什么！
No, wait...
不，等等...
No!
不！
Mr. Krabs, can I see
the movie now...
蟹老板，我可以看看吗
电影现在...
Please?
请？
Of course, you can, lad.
当然，你可以，小伙子。
You just gotta
give me one penny.
你只需要
给我一分钱。
But, but...
但是，但是……
But... I really
don't  have  a penny.
但是……我真的
一分钱都没有。
Oh, that's too bad.
哦，那太糟糕了。
I really wanted
to see that movie.
我真的很想要
看那部电影。
Oh, well.
那好吧。
Good evening.
晚上好。
And... welcome to the...
并且...欢迎来到...
Krusty Krab Semi-Annual
Charity Night.
蟹堡王半年刊
慈善之夜。
Squidward?
章鱼哥？
You look beautiful.
你看起来很漂亮。
: Let me show
you to your table.
: 让我展示一下
你到你的桌子上。
My table?
我的桌子？
Whoa, fancy.
哇，太棒了。
My very own name tag.
我自己的名牌。
Hello, and welcome to
a very important evening.
您好，欢迎来到
一个非常重要的夜晚。
Tonight's evening is entitled:
今晚的题目是：
"Pennies for the Penniless."
“给身无分文的人提供便士。”
And before the following
images are shown
以及在以下内容之前
显示图像
I would ask each of you
我会问你们每个人
to look not with your eyes
不用眼睛看
but with your heart.
但用你的心。
Krabs: Three dimes.
蟹蟹：三毛钱。
Two Nickels.
两枚镍币。
One quarter.
四分之一。
Zero pennies.
零便士。
And since I realize
the images seen here tonight
自从我意识到
今晚在这里看到的图像
may be wretchedly hideous
可能非常丑陋
I am going to tell you what you
can do to end this travesty.
我要告诉你什么
可以做些什么来结束这种嘲讽。
You can donate one penny
to me, Mr. Krabs.
你可以捐一分钱
对我来说，蟹老板。
Also known as Mr. Krabs,
the man who doesn't have one.
也被称为蟹老板，
一个没有的人。
Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板？
Yes?
是的？
I would like to donate a penny.
我愿意捐一分钱。
You would?
你会吗？
If I only had one.
如果我只有一个就好了。
Penny, got to...
佩妮，必须...
... Penny.
……佩妮。
Not gonna...
不会...
Ha-ha.
哈哈。
Ahh!
啊！
Krabs: Hee-hee-hee-hee...
螃蟹：嘿嘿嘿嘿……
Now we...
现在我们...
Hiding it...
隐藏它...
Somewhere.
某处。
Hiding it.
隐藏它。
Hiding... it.
隐藏……它。
Hiding it?
隐藏它？
Meow.
喵。
What's that?
那是什么？
You.
你。
You know where.
你知道在哪里。
Meow.
喵。
Tell where.
告诉哪里。
Hiding it inside.
把它藏在里面。
In there... Somewhere.
在那里……某处。
Mr. Krabs.
蟹老板。
What is this metal
detector doing on the floor?
这种金属是什么
探测器在地板上做什么？
He should only be stored
on special racks...
他应该只被存储
在特殊的架子上...
And you're not
wearing your metal detector
handling gloves.
而你不是
佩戴金属探测器
处理手套。
SpongeBob, I...
海绵宝宝，我...
I... I, I just
wanted that penny
我...我我只是
想要那一分钱
you found on the
street, yesterday.
你发现在
街道，昨天。
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦，对不起。
Mr. Krabs, that wasn't
a penny  .
蟹老板，那不是
一分钱。
It wasn't?
不是吗？
That was just a dried-up piece
of gum for my collection.
那只是一块干涸的碎片
我收藏的口香糖。
I think it's peppermint.
我认为是薄荷。
: Aha!
：啊哈！
Ah-hoo... Oh-ho.
啊呼……哦呼。
I feel so relieved.
我感觉很轻松。
There was no penny after all.
终究是没有一分钱。
Ah, well, I'll be going now.
啊，好吧，我现在就走了。
You can keep the metal
detector, SpongeBob- see ya.
你可以保留金属
探测器，海绵宝宝——再见。
Thanks, Mr. Krabs.
谢谢，蟹老板。
Here, Gary, you
can play with that.
在这里，加里，你
可以玩那个。
Hey, this isn't gum at all.
嘿，这根本不是口香糖。
Just a dumb old $500 bill.
只是一张愚蠢的旧500美元钞票。
This won't go with
my chewed-up gum collection.
这不会与
我咀嚼过的口香糖收藏。
SpongeBob: Ah, well,
good night, Gary.
海绵宝宝：啊，好吧，
晚安，加里。
That penny- must've buried
it around here somewhere.
那一分钱——肯定已经埋了
它就在这附近的某个地方。
I'll just have to keep digging.
我只得继续挖掘。
Mrs. Puff: Remember, class...
帕芙老师：同学们，请记住……
There is only one way
to park a boat:
只有一种方法
停泊船只：
the safe way.
安全的方式。
You now see the importance
of proper steering
你现在明白了重要性
正确的转向
And a properly
calibrated anchor.
以及一个正确的
校准锚。
Which brings us
to the subject of
这给我们带来了
rudder maintenance.
舵的维护。
Barnacles, just as we were
getting to the nitty-gritty.
藤壶，就像我们一样
进入实质内容。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Remember, we will
not be here tomorrow.
请记住，我们会
明天不在这里。
We will be going on a field trip
to the boating museum.
我们将去实地考察
到划船博物馆。
Now run along, kids.
现在就跑吧，孩子们。
Students: Yay!
学生：耶！
Wow, the boating museum.
哇，划船博物馆。
Maybe tomorrow
if I can impress Mrs. Puff
也许明天
如果我能给泡芙太太留下好印象
with an extensive knowledge
of boating history
知识渊博
划船历史
she'll give me a boating
license on the spot.
她会给我划船
现场颁发许可证。
Vroom-vroom.
呜呜呜。
See you tomorrow,
Mrs. P.
明天见，
P 女士
Neptune, give me strength.
海王星，请赐予我力量。
Let's see...
让我们来看看...
Huh, there she is.
哈，她在那儿。
Whoa!
哇！
Oh!
哦！
Meow?
喵？
What is this, Gary?
这是什么，加里？
Why it's the complete history
of all boating ever
为什么这是完整的历史
有史以来所有划船的
and I'm going
to memorize it tonight
我要去
今晚要记住它
for the big
field trip tomorrow.
对于大
明天实地考察。
I'm perfectly capable
of reading 7,400 pages
我完全有能力
阅读 7,400 页
and still getting my
required eight hours of sleep
仍然得到我的
需要八个小时的睡眠
before the bus picks me up
promptly at 8:00 A.M. tomorrow.
在巴士接我之前
上午 8:00 准时明天。
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'd like to get started.
现在请原谅我
我想开始。
All right, let's see
好吧，让我们看看
what this little pamphlet
is all about.
这本小册子是什么
就是这样。
Chapter One:
第一章：
"In the beginning,
Neptune created the sail.
“一开始，
海王星创造了帆。
French Man: 7:59 A.M.
法国人：上午 7:59
"...but such tragedies
will be avoided
“……但是这样的悲剧
将会被避免
with the flying boat
of the future... The end."
与飞艇
未来……终结。”
Time for a little
shut-eye before...
有时间一点
之前先闭眼...
Mrs. Puff, can't this
wait till tomorrow?
泡芙女士，这可不可以
等到明天吗？
Hang on a minute.
等一下。
This is tomorrow.
这是明天。
Wait, wait.
等等，等等。
Hey!
嘿！
Mrs. Puff...
泡芙夫人……
Please stop the bus.
请停车。
What was that?
那是什么？
Nothing, uh...
没什么，呃...
Just keep driving.
继续开车吧。
Step on it!
踩它！
SpongeBob: Wait!
海绵宝宝：等等！
Whew.
呼。
No worries, I made it.
不用担心，我做到了。
SpongeBob, you look terrible.
海绵宝宝，你看起来很糟糕。
I assure you, I am
well-rested and ready to learn.
我向你保证，我是
休息好并准备好学习。
Who knows, Mrs. Puff,
before the day is out
谁知道呢，帕夫夫人，
在这一天结束之前
you may have learned
something yourself.
你可能已经学会了
你自己的东西。
Hey, Mrs. Puff?
嘿，普芙夫人？
Yes, SpongeBob?
是的，海绵宝宝？
I made
this for you.
我做了
这是给你的。
this- the H.M.S. Pinafore.
这——H.M.S.围裙。
At 1/8,427 scale,
of course.
在 1/8,427 比例下，
当然。
Thank you, SpongeBob.
谢谢你，海绵宝宝。
Mrs. Puff?
泡芙夫人？
Do you know how many rowers
it takes to propel a trireme?
你知道有多少赛艇运动员吗
推动三层桨战舰需要什么？
Well, that would be...
嗯，那就是……
Do you know which boat
is the fastest on record?
你知道哪条船吗
是有记录以来最快的吗？
Wasn't that the...
那不是那个...
Did you know
that in the future
你知道吗
那个在未来
all boats will be
powered by dolphin manure?
所有的船都会
由海豚粪便提供动力？
Did you know that the H.M.S.
Bluetoes was originally
你知道 H.M.S.
蓝音最初是
a racing boat before it
became the royal family's
private yacht?
前面有一艘赛艇
成为了皇室的
私人游艇？
Do you know
what scuttling is?
你知道吗
什么是凿空？
What's bigger-
a flotilla or a fleet?
什么更大-
舰队还是舰队？
Did you know...
你可知道...
Ever been on
a pont... Ohh...
曾经上过
一座桥……哦……
Ow.
噢。
We're here.
我们到了。
Mrs. Puff: Welcome, class,
to the boating museum.
普芙老师：欢迎同学们，
到划船博物馆。
This  enormous  vessel
这艘巨大的船只
was once the largest
in all the seas.
曾经是最大的
在所有的海洋中。
But now that it's been
converted into a museum
但既然已经这样了
改建为博物馆
it no longer moves.
它不再动了。
Actually it gets taken to port
once a year for maintenance.
实际上它被带到了港口
每年一次进行维护。
If you don't mind, SpongeBob
如果你不介意的话，海绵宝宝
I'll  be doing
the teaching today.
我会做
今天的教学。
No problemo, Mrs. P.
没问题，P 女士。
Mrs. Puff: Here it is, class.
普芙老师：同学们，就是这里。
The most extensive collection
最广泛的收藏
of seafaring
history ever assembled.
航海的
历史曾经聚集。
From giant naval vessels
来自巨型海军舰艇
to more modest craft,
like this clamming boat.
到更朴素的工艺，
就像这艘蛤蜊船。
I'd say this baby can hold
up to 10 clam fishers.
我想说这个宝宝可以抱
最多 10 名蛤渔民。
Uh, sure, SpongeBob.
呃，当然，海绵宝宝。
Why, I bet they reel in
up to 50 clams a day.
为什么，我打赌他们会陷入困境
每天最多 50 个蛤蜊。
Moving along.
继续前进。
Over here we have
the "Sandy Nub."
在这里我们有
“桑迪努布”。
It was a cargo ship used to
bring back exotic spices
这是一艘曾经的货船
带回异国香料
from faraway lands.
来自遥远的土地。
With two direct
acting steam turbines
有两个直接
作用蒸汽轮机
producing 6,500 horsepower
产生 6,500 马力
geared up to triple screws.
配备三重螺丝。
It'll get your spices
where they need to go.
它会得到你的香料
他们需要去哪里。
: Thank you,
again, SpongeBob.
：谢谢你，
又是海绵宝宝。
It's working.
它正在发挥作用。
She's noticing
my vast knowledge.
她注意到了
我渊博的知识。
I can now taste the sweet,
sweet lamination of
a fresh boating license.
现在我能尝到甜头了
甜蜜的层压
新的划船执照。
This class...
这堂课...
is the "Lady Scallion."
就是“葱娘子”。
Named after the captain's
strict diet of scallions
以船长的名字命名
严格限制大葱的饮食
of which the crew
complained and the captain's
odor strongly resembled.
其中船员
抱怨和船长的
气味非常相似。
For four years this brigantine
四年来，这艘双桅帆船
explored distant lands
探索遥远的土地
discovering places unknown to
anyone besides the people
发现未知的地方
除了人民之外的任何人
who already lived there.
谁已经住在那里了。
: Ooh.
：哦。
Are you ready to give me
that license yet, Mrs. Puff?
你准备好给我了吗
帕芙女士，驾照还没拿到吗？
Oh, you're gonna
get it, all right.
哦，你会
明白了，好吧。
I knew it.
我就知道。
: OK, this
is the end of the tour.
: 好的，这个
旅程结束了。
Anything to add, SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝，还有什么要补充的吗？
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Oh, boy, here it is,
the main controls.
哦，孩子，在这里，
主要控制。
Just look at
all this stuff.
看看
所有这些东西。
There's the triple oscillator
这是三重振荡器
and there's the hoist pulley,
and there's the booby trap.
还有起重滑轮，
还有诱杀装置。
And there's the
long range mast knob.
还有就是
远程桅杆旋钮。
And there's a hot dog
with extra mustard.
还有一个热狗
加额外的芥末。
And there is
the starter mechanism.
并且有
启动机构。
That, right there.
那个，就在那里。
A-C.
交流。
That's short for automatic
"causition auto".
这是自动的缩写
“因果自动”。
And that's fancy-fancy talk for
这就是花哨的谈话
let's get this party started...
让我们开始这个聚会吧...
Like instantly.
就像瞬间一样。
Deh-deh-deh, deh-deh, dah.
哒哒哒，哒哒哒。
Deh-deh-deh, dah.
呸呸呸，呸。
Whoo.
呼。
Man, I'm glad that's over.
伙计，我很高兴一切都结束了。
Oh, that's a nice touch.
哦，这真是一个很好的接触。
What a soothing
projection screen.
多么令人心旷神怡
投影屏幕。
That's not a projection screen.
那不是投影屏幕。
SpongeBob, stop it
right now.
海绵宝宝，别这样
现在。
Yes, ma'am  .
是的，女士。
Oh, sweet Poseidon.
哦，可爱的波塞冬。
Move aside.
移到一边。
I gotta stop this ship before
it plows into Bikini Bottom.
我得先阻止这艘船
它陷入比基尼底部。
Oh, uh, let's see.
哦，呃，让我们看看。
The first thing to turn off
is the, uh, ohh...
首先要关闭的
是，呃，哦...
...dear Neptune.
...亲爱的海王星。
I've never driven anything
this advanced before.
我从来没有开过任何东西
这是之前先进的。
SpongeBob, I hope you knew
what you were talking about
海绵宝宝，我希望你知道
你在说什么
because it's up
to you know.
因为它起来了
你知道。
OK.
好的。
Mrs. Puff: We don't
have much time.
泡芙女士：我们不
有很多时间。
In a few minutes
we'll be flattening
几分钟后
我们将会变平
millions of innocent lives.
数以百万计无辜者的生命。
Innocent lives?
无辜的生命？
And you're the only one
that can save them.
而你是唯一的一个
这可以拯救他们。
The only one
唯一的一个
that can save them?
那可以拯救他们吗？
Yes, now, what
I want you to do is
是的，现在，什么
我想让你做的是
tighten the gurneys.
收紧轮床。
Then survey
the poop deck.
然后调查
船尾甲板。
Then...
然后...
I know what to do.
我知道该怎么做。
I read a book.
我读了一本书。
Chapter One:
"Batten Down the Hatches."
第一章：
“把舱门封好。”
Next, lower anchor.
接下来，下锚。
No, the anchor's stuck.
不，锚被卡住了。
I'm going to have
to free it manually.
我将会有
手动释放它。
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
Doh!
哎哟！
Done and done.
完成了，完成了。
Thirdly: "Utter a hearty
seaman's laugh".
第三：“发自内心的
海员的笑声”。
Oh, my gravy.
哦，我的肉汁。
He even knows the hearty laugh.
他甚至还知道爽朗的笑声。
He  has  been doing his homework.
他一直在做作业。
And finally,
the  coup de grace.
最后，
致命一击。
The only way to park
the largest ship ever built
停车的唯一途径
有史以来建造的最大的船
is by performing the reverse
seven/20 tailspin.
是通过执行相反的操作
七/20 混乱。
But that's never even
been attempted before.
但这从来都不是
之前已经尝试过。
You're right, it hasn't.
你说得对，还没有。
Not until now.
直到现在。
SpongeBob, I don't know how
海绵宝宝，我不知道怎么办
but you did it.
但你做到了。
You saved us all.
你拯救了我们所有人。
Mrs. Puff: Oh, let's
get off this thing.
泡芙夫人：哦，我们来吧
摆脱这件事。
And the way you pulled the
anchor out...  genius.
还有你拉的方式
锚定...天才。
I never thought
I'd say this but...
我从没想过
我想说这个但是...
here's your driver's license.
这是你的驾驶执照。
Oh, boy.
哦，男孩。
At long last.
终于。
Man: What are you
two doing here?
男：你是什么东西
两个人在这里做什么？
Huh?
啊？
No one should be on board
船上不应有人
while I'm tugging
the museum into port.
当我拉扯的时候
博物馆进入港口。
You mean, he wasn't
driving this thing at all?
你的意思是，他不是
驾驶这东西吗？
Heck, no.
哎呀，不。
Now, don't get
so down, kid.
现在，不要得到
这么沮丧，孩子。
Look, for your false bravery
看吧，看看你虚假的勇敢
I'm giving you your
honorary sea legs, OK?
我给你你的
荣誉海腿，好吗？
Come on, let me buy
you an ice cream.
来吧，让我买
你一个冰淇淋。
Oh, gosh...
Headlights are on.
哦，天哪...
车头灯亮了。
Both: Don't touch
anything, you twit!
两人：别碰
什么都行，你这个混蛋！
Run!
跑步！
Good thing you studied.
还好你学了。